# **Matthew Bell**

Seattle, WA — 636-352-8926 — matthew.bell.290@gmail.com — Github Account — LinkedIn — mjbell.io

#### SUMMARY

Software Engineer with 2 years of relevant experience, specializing in Ruby and Ruby on Rails. Comfortable at a Software Engineer 2 level in a with a fast paced, fully remote startup work environment that requires many hats to be worn. Resourceful and tenacious at contributing to the efficiency and completion of application features. Effective communicator and team player.

#### RELEVANT EXPERIENCE

## Voy

## Software Engineer

April 2018 - Present — Seattle, WA (100% remote)

- Collaborated with the VP of Engineering to architect and build the Ruby on Rails API
- Built an authentication engine, including two factor auth for the frontend and the backend
- Implemented the transaction system for both an internal service as well as a blockchain
- Architected and implemented the frontend for providers to create their rewards program
- Wrote and implemented tech specs for API endpoints to support the React frontend
- Participated heavily in the development of the agile process
- Collaborated effectively with a 100% remote team, including product managers, designers, and engineers

#### **General Assembly**

Associate Instructor — Software Engineering Immersive

January 2018 - April 2018 — Seattle, WA

- Educated and mentored a class of 14 on in demand skills in the web development world
- Taught full stack web development, starting with the basics of front-end HTML, CSS, and JavaScript, to the stacks including MERN (Mongo, Express, React, Node) and Python/Django
- Lead lectures on HTML/CSS, Git/Github, jQuery, SQL and NoSQL databases, Testing and Test Driven Development, Regular Expressions, several React topics
- Lead lectures on computer science topics including Stacks, Queues and Linked Lists
- Pair programmed with students to talk through and solve complicated problems in their projects and deliverables

#### American Councils for International Education

Assistant Logistical Coordinator

July 2015 - July 2017 — Washington, D.C.

- Became familiar with various programming languages, frameworks, and database management systems, including Ruby, Ruby on Rails, PHP, MySQL, AWS, and Drupal.
- Wrote complicated SQL queries to unlock data from our database to prepare reports
- Authored Ruby scripts to automate Microsoft Word document processing
- Created meaningful documentation to improve department collaboration as well as client understanding of new and existing procedures
- Collaborated closely with department developers in order to model out database schemas and communicate client needs

#### **EDUCATION**

## **General Assembly**

## Software Engineering Immersive

August 2017 - November 2017 — Seattle, WA

- 720+ hours dedicated professional development
- Reinforced fundamentals of HTML/CSS/Javascript
- Built a 95% jQuery checkers game
- Engineered a full-stack app loan visualization app with Node, Express, PostgreSQL, and D3.js
- Collaborated with a team to build a MERN (MongoDB, Express, React, Node) app as Git Master
- Architected a Ruby on Rails app creating a google calendar integration app for bulk google calendar event implementation using an integrated spreadsheet.

# **University of Missouri**

Philosophy & International Studies

August 2010 - May 2014 — Columbia, MO

- Undergraduate Philosophy emphasis in logic and reasoning
- Undergraduate International Studies emphasis in Middle-Eastern studies and Peace Studies

# University of Jordan

Arabic Study Abroad

December 2012 - April 2013 — Amman, Jordan

- Deepened understanding of Middle-Eastern studies
- Reinforced Arabic to the Intermediate level

### **SKILLS**

Top 5: Ruby, Ruby on Rails, Javascript, React, Test Driven Development

PostgreSQL, MySQL, Git, Github, Python, Golang, Node, Express.js, Django, Sideqik,

Other Skills: Redis, d3.js, jQuery, Slack, Trello, Blockchain, Ethereum, AJAX, RESTful APIs, Object

Oriented Programming, Agile, Test Driven Development